Bravery is contagious
The Dark Horse is a drama, history film directed by James Napier Robertson.
One-time Maori speed-chess champ, Genesis Potini, lives with a bi-polar disorder and must overcome prejudice and
violence in the battle to save his struggling chess club, his family and ultimately, himself.
Genesis, played by Cliff Curtis.
Mana, played by James Rolleston.
Noble, played by Kirk Torrance.
Nurse, played by Sia Trokenheim.
Clive, played by Andrew Grainger.
Jedi, played by Xavier Horan.
The Dark Horse is a 2014 New Zealand drama film written and directed by James
Napier Robertson and starring Cliff Curtis and James Rolleston.
It won Best Picture, Best Director, Best Screenplay, Best Actor, Best Supporting Actor and Best Score at the 2014 New Zealand Film Awards, Best Film at the 2015 Seattle International Film Festival (SIFF), 2015 San Francisco International Film
Festival (SFIFF) and 2015 Rotterdam International Film Festival (IFFR), was New York Times Critics' Pick and Time Magazine Critics' Pick, and was labeled by leading New Zealand critics as "One of the greatest New Zealand films ever made".
It premiered at the 2014 Toronto International Film Festival (TIFF),
and was created by production company Four Knights Film.
The film was released theatrically in the U.S.
by Broad Green Pictures on 1 April 2016.
The film explores themes of chess, new zealand, based on true story, auckland.
The tone is emotional.